[♪ western music plays]
[Harold, in English]
Everywhere you turn in Monument Valley,
it's always magical.
When I go away, I always want to come back
and look at it again and so on.
[narrator] It's the special summer break
Noel organized
for the Travis Japan members.
At the foot of the Rocky Mountains
where the desert breeze blows
lies the real America
the members have yet to see.
The Travis Japan members except for Noel
divide up into two groups
and head to their final destination.
Sedona, Arizona.
Noel sets out to Sedona on his own
before the others
to quietly prepare
a warm welcome for them.
[♪ opening theme music plays]
Travis Japan
SUMMER VACATION!! IN THE USA
[♪ rock music plays]
Thanks for routing me.
[narrator]
Picking up where we last left off,
we follow Team A's Chaka, Umi, and Shizu
as they travel through Monument Valley,
where the Navajo Nation,
the largest Native American tribe
in the United States, resides.
[in English] Monument Valley, Utah.
[♪ rock music continues]
[in Japanese]
They drive through the vast wilderness
of this 337,000 square kilometer desert.
The classic American landscape
seems to stretch endlessly.
[♪ rock music stops]
[Umi] There. Look, look. Look, it's tiny.
-Oh, really?
-[Umi] See? It's a tiny place.
You've gotta open your eyes
real wide to find it.
We drive all the way down… And stop here.
[Umi] Hold on. That's pretty far.
[exclaims]
It's the first Japanese food
we've had in a while.
-[Shizu, in English] Okay. Let's go.
-Let's go!
Let's go!
[Shizu whoops]
[♪ upbeat music plays]
[♪ music continues]
"Cameron".
[Shizu, in Japanese] What, what?
[in English] "Indian arts and…"
[narrator, in Japanese]
This is a historical post
with almost a century behind it.
Originally used by traders to barter
goods with the Native American tribes,
it now preserves
the indigenous traditions and culture
by functioning as a living, historic site.
-[Shizu, in English] Hi.
-Sorry, guys, I blew it.
-Hey, nice to meet you.
-Hi.
-Thank you.
-Very nice to meet you too.
-I'm Chaka.
-Chaka?
-I'm Umi. Yeah.
-Umi.
-I'm Shizu.
-You're Shizu.
-Very, very nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
Welcome. I'm glad you guys are here.
-Thank you so much.
-A lot of the kids inside here
-are very excited about you coming.
-Wow. Yay!
-We are so excited.
-They were showing the picture
and everything. So that's wonderful.
So, before we go in,
-can I show you something?
-Yeah.
-Thank you.
-Let's go this way.
[Shizu] We want to see that. Whoo!
In 1934, the Navajo Nation
was expanded
to include this particular property.
So we're kind of like a little island of…
All right, so, one more time.
-[shop owner laughs]
-[Shizu] Right there is good.
Hubert Richardson built
the trading post back here in 1911,
because they built this bridge.
[Umi, Shizu, Chaka] Whoa.
So this is the whole reason
why all of this is here.
In the old days,
when this was built in 1911,
The people that would come to trade here,
sometimes they had to come
for days on-on wagons with, uh, horses.
So at the time we had, uh, guest hogans
or guest homes
that they could stay in for several days
while they completed their trade
at the trading post.
And the old traders,
they weren't just traders,
they weren't just trading merchandise
and, uh, livestock for dry goods.
They were also kind of like liaisons
for their culture, for the United States.
Things were very, very different out here.
Um, and a lot of times,
the local people didn't understand
what they were looking at.
So the trader would interpret letters,
papers and help them in that way.
I'll show you
the main building over there. The…
This was the old motel building
but we've turned it into
an antique Native American arts gallery.
-Can we see? [cheers]
-Yeah, of course.
-I would love to. It would be my pleasure.
-[Shizu, in Japanese] They sell antiques.
[Umi, in English] Thank you.
So that's what we have over here.
We have a mixture of the contemporary art,
the really fine contemporary
Native American art,
as well as, uh, the antiques that they
actually made and used themselves,
you know, 100 years ago.
And then over the winter, uh,
destroyed all their…
These were all handmade.
-[Umi] All handmade?
-Mm-hmm.
And then they were made
for themselves like this one.
But sometimes they also made
them like this one,
that would be for trade when
the railroads came through around 1890.
But sometime around 1930 to 1940,
the knowledge of how to make these
was lost.
And, so,
there will be no more of these baskets.
-No one remembers how to make them.
-No more?
-And that blanket runs $250,000.
-[Chaka] What?
-[Shizu] What? Huh?
-[Umi] Wait.
How much is it that in yen?
[Chaka]
One, ten, 100, 1,000, 10,000, 100,000…
-Four?
-About a whopping 40 million yen.
-Oh, by far.
-Holy mackerel!
-That's crazy expensive.
-[shop owner] It's a lot.
-He can… He can buy.
-[shop owner laughs]
-[shop owner] He can buy it?
-No, no.
-Hey.
-[Umi] He has a…
[Shizu, shop owner laugh]
[Umi] Wow.
-[Shizu, in Japanese] Wow, look at it.
-Cool! Wow. I love it.
Hey, wait…
[shop owner, in English] The value
of this weaving is really intrinsic.
The value of the weaving
is its history being… having been woven.
The United States government
was trying to change their culture.
They were trying to turn them from
Native Americans into white farmers.
And this Navajo woman,
when she was at Bosque Redondo,
I don't know how hard the march was
for her but I know it was hard.
To me, this is her way of saying,
-"No. I'm not going to change."
-[Chaka] Yeah.
"This is who I am.
And I'm gonna weave this here."
[Chaka] This seem to say a lot of things.
That's… that's pain, that's brave,
a lot of things.
That's exactly right.
I'm glad to hear you say that.
A lot of people don't really understand.
[Noel, in Japanese] Through hearing the
rich stories about this region's people
from locals like him,
I've come to see
that the decorations and accessories
we often regard as purely aesthetic
are deeply rooted in culture and history.
It suits you. The headpiece
complements your facial features.
Yeah, it's a perfect fit.
[shop owner] These are dream catchers.
The design itself is probably from
the Plains Indians…
-[Chaka] Mm-hmm.
-…but the tradition is that
these are a web that catches
your nightmares, your bad dreams.
-Uh-huh.
-So at night,
your bad dreams,
they get caught in this web…
-I see. Yeah.
-…and they can't get to your head.
-Uh-huh.
-And then in the morning,
the sun comes and washes them away.
-Uh-huh.
-But your good dreams
-are able to get through.
-Oh, I see that.
-This is pretty cool.
-It's a catch for the bad dream.
Yes. Catches the bad dreams,
they get caught in the net.
The good dreams go around the
sides and can come through the bottom.
-Oh, I think that's here. Uh-huh.
-Yes.
-Yeah.
-Only a good dream.
-Yes.
-I see now.
-Anywhere in your bedroom is fine.
-Uh-huh.
Yeah.
[shop owner] So these are also made
by the Diné, or the Navajo.
-[Umi] Yep.
-Each one of these pieces is handmade.
[Umi] Handmade.
Oh, Native American handmade.
Mm-hmm. Now the pot itself is a ceramic.
It's kind of like the, uh, uh…
-the canvas for a painting.
-Uh-huh.
So they take this pot,
and then they color it,
and then they etch each one
of these tiny lines by hand.
Whoa.
We work with a family
of Navajo pottery artists.
So it's a family thing that's passed on
from mother to daughter to daughter.
Mm-hmm. Whoa.
It is so…
Generation… Over the generations.
Exactly.
-Yes.
-Whoa.
-Most Native American art is like that.
-Mmm.
You don't go to school for four years
or eight years to learn how to do it.
-Oh, yes.
-You work with your grandparents
and your parents
and other artists in the area.
That's how you learn it.
Through apprenticeship.
So these are also another
Navajo or Diné tradition.
Um, these juniper berries here…
these are the seeds from the juniper tree.
-Mm-hmm.
-Kind of a conifer.
They fall on the ground
and then the ants will eat them hollow.
And the Navajo, they pick these up
and they pierce the other end
to make them into beads.
And the tradition is,
this protects you
from, uh, people who have bad intentions
or are trying to bad things to you
or just are not nice people.
It protects you from them.
Keeps that away.
They call them, uh, cedar beads.
Sometimes they call them
ghost beads as well.
So cool.
[Chaka, in Japanese] He explained
a different item to each of us.
[Umi] About the ceramics
and whatnot, yep, too.
You should bring it back with you.
How about… this
will be my souvenir for Kura.
-Good idea, it's right down his alley.
-It's his style.
Then I'll grab something for Shime…
Or Genta? Which one?
-I'm claiming the dream catcher.
-Well, yeah, but…
Okay, you get something for Shime.
I'll get Genta a dream catcher, yeah.
-Then we'll decide the souvenir for Noel.
-We'll all decide, the three of us.
Okay. Got it. Bye-bye!
It matches the decorations at his house.
It has blue in it.
It'll catch all his nightmares
so that only the good dreams can pass.
[laughs]
[♪ upbeat music plays]
Uh…
Oh, look. I like this one. It's cute.
I choose this one.
This one.
[Chaka] Oh, 100%.
It's precious.
What do you think?
-Yep, this one.
-[laughs]
It's a done deal. This one's for Shime.
[♪ music continues]
Oh, how about this one?
[Shizu] A cat.
-[Chaka] How nice. Kitty-cat.
-Look, a cat statue.
-It's nice. But it's…
-And it's turquoise.
-Perfect then.
-It's got nothing to do with
the Native culture, but, oh, well.
-Well, I suppose…
-Yeah.
…it's one of the ceramic cats for Noel.
-This one it is. Meow, meow.
-Oh, and Noel has two cats.
-And this one, too.
-Noel has two cats, this is perfect.
We've got a pair of cats.
-They're symmetrical.
-[Shizu] Symmetrical!
Meow, meow.
[Genta] Over here?
-How early.
-It's open already.
-They open at 6:30.
-Thanks.
Americano?
-[barista] Americano?
-Yeah.
[barista] Do you want that iced or hot?
-Uh, Ice. Ice, please.
-[barista] Great.
-Thanks.
-Thank you so much.
Thank you.
[in Japanese] Oh.
Ready for today's message?
Ready.
"Today, you are visiting
a historic railroad town."
-Railroad?
-Railroad.
"But you won't be boarding
the locomotive until tomorrow.
Enjoy exploring the area today."
And, "Just a heads-up.
-Genta…
-Yes.
…know when to stop."
Well, you heard.
What is he talking about?
A ride on the locomotive…
Oh, that's tomorrow.
-Yep, tomorrow.
-We're boarding a train tomorrow.
-But for today, we're only sightseeing?
-Thank you.
-Sightseeing?
-Oh, do we have a free day?
I think that's the idea, yeah.
"Genta, know when to stop."
Sightseeing today, locomotive tomorrow.
-Genta, know when to stop.
[Genta] Hey now.
Just…
[Genta] What?
There's no way to tell
what he's referring to at this stage.
[Machu] It's like Noel prepared riddles
for us to solve.
-[Genta laughs]
-He's toying with us.
-He's messing with us.
-Is that what that is?
He got us good.
[Machu] It's as if he's daring us
to crack a puzzle.
-Only way to find out is to start.
-He's giving us riddles?
-Well, if we walk around…
-Walk around, and…
Let's explore the town as we go along.
-Shall we?
-Shime, your…
Yeah.
Do you wanna finish it,
-or ask for a doggie bag?
-I'll get a bag.
-Yep.
-[in English] Excuse me.
Uh, I want a to-go? Takeout?
-[barista] Have a great day.
-Yeah. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
[in Japanese] Time to explore the town.
Bread… Bread. Bread's delicious.
I've always wanted to commute
with a coffee in one hand.
-[Genta] It came true.
-Good for you.
Seriously though.
What did Noel mean, "Know when to stop?"
-[Machu] Yeah, now I'm curious.
-[Genta] Hmm.
[Machu] Mind if I start driving?
-[Shime] Go.
-[Machu] All righty.
[Shime, in English] Let's go!
-[Genta] Let's go. Let's go.
-[Shime] Let's go.
[Shime, in Japanese]
You're getting the hang of driving.
[Machu] Am I?
[Genta] You look cool.
-Give us a shout, Shime.
-[in English] Let's go!
[Genta laughs]
[Machu, in Japanese] It's the best!
[all laugh, cheer]
[♪ blues music plays]
[♪ music continues]
[Noel] I'm in Colorado,
the state with the highest altitude.
The people reside in a city
nested in the Rocky Mountains,
which reaches 4,000 meters in elevation.
To the west, tucked away
in the rugged San Juan Mountains
is a tiny town called Durango.
[narrator, in English] Durango, Colorado.
[train whistle blows]
[narrator, in Japanese] Founded in 1881,
Durango began as a railroad town built
to serve the gold and silver mines
of the San Juan.
The town is dotted with Victorian-era
buildings reminiscent of the Old Frontier.
[Machu] Here we go, here we go!
[Genta] We're here!
-Yeah!
[♪ upbeat music plays]
[♪ music continues]
What a fancy building.
Oh, super fancy.
[Machu laughs]
Ready?
Say cheese.
[camera shutter clicks]
[Genta laughs]
[Shime laughs]
[Machu] Great.
Say cheese.
[camera shutter clicks]
[♪ music stops]
This is the hotel we're staying at.
-Amazing.
-Wow!
Let's go check in.
[Shime] Wow, what a gorgeous hotel.
[narrator] This hotel
has provided beds for travelers
since the days of the Old Frontier.
We'll be immersed in history.
-Right?
-[receptionist, in English] Hi.
-Hi.
-Hello.
[narrator, in Japanese]
From its antique interiors
to the hotel staff's period uniforms,
the hotel feels like
a window into the bygone days.
-Do you like it? Yes.
-[Machu] Yeah, of course.
We like it.
It's pretty cool.
[Genta] Yes.
So we opened our doors in 1887.
-Mmm.
-1887.
[receptionist] Yeah, we're the second
oldest business in Durango.
The first one being the railroad.
-[Shime] Wow. Cool.
-Yeah.
-So we've been around for a little while.
-[all laugh]
[Genta] Yeah.
[receptionist]
So your room number is right here.
[Machu] Okay.
[receptionist]
And I'm just gonna hand you these then.
-Thanks so much.
-Thank you!
-Appreciate it.
-[receptionist] Enjoy.
-Thank you so much.
-Have a good day.
-Hello.
-Nice to meet you.
-Welcome to the Historic Strater Hotel.
-Hello.
-Nice to meet you.
-Can I show you a couple of hiding spots?
-What? What spot?
-Yeah.
[Genta] Is it a box?
[Genta] What is…
[Shime, Machu, Genta exclaim]
-What is this?
-[guide] We got some candy.
-[Machu] Candy!
-[Genta] Can I get this one?
-[guide] Yes.
-[Genta] Really?
-[Machu] Really?
-[Genta] Yeah.
-[Shime] What a kind man.
-Thank you.
-[guide] You're very welcome.
This is something else.
I've never seen such
a trick in all my life.
[in English] Why… Why make it?
Well, back in the day, people didn't
trust banks or banks weren't available.
So they would build hiding spots
to hide their valuables
like keys and money
and jewelry and stuff like that.
-Mmm.
-So these are just three examples
of what we put in to show people
what they would've done back in the day.
[in Japanese] Oh, I see.
What a fun little gimmick.
Yeah, it's like we're in a movie.
And let me show you another secret.
[in English] Oh, okay.
-[in Japanese] Wow.
-It's amazing.
-[in English] Where?
-[in Japanese] What? There's more?
[Shime, Machu, Genta exclaim]
Incredible.
[guide] So these were done with
little miniatures as you can see.
Um, a lot of the front desk folks
and a lot of the maintenance guys
got together and decided
to make this into another spare bedroom.
-[Genta] Whoa.
-Just for fun,
-but mainly for the little kids.
-Yeah.
[in Japanese] Is this your room, Machu?
[in English] Is this my room?
-Yes, it is.
-Okay. [laughs]
This is where
you'll be checking into tonight.
-See you tomorrow, Machu.
-Off I go.
See you tomorrow.
[Genta laughs]
[in Japanese]
You'll break it! You'll break it!
You don't fit. Really, you don't!
-Oh, I bet children get a kick out of it.
-For sure.
This place is fun
for the entire family, kids included.
There's something for everyone here.
-Amazing!
-[in English] I love it. I love it.
-[in Japanese] That's super fun.
-Amazing.
-[guide] Yep.
-Yeah.
-[in Japanese] Thank you.
-All right, let me show you
another one right over here.
This is my third secret hiding spot.
[Shime, Machu, Genta exclaim]
[in Japanese] Here, too?
[in English] Isn't that cool?
Now again, they would've put money, keys,
jewelry, even a gun.
-Wow. That is amazing.
-Interesting.
-Isn't that cool?
-Yeah, cool.
Yeah, it's so cool.
[in Japanese] Wow.
[Noel] The name "Durango" originates
from the Basque word "urango",
which means, "the city of water."
[water flowing]
True to its name, a river flows
through the heart of the city,
and along its riverbanks
is a nature retreat.
This river's pristine, abundant waters
have bestowed a boon to the city.
And this boon is…
Genta's favorite drink,
beer.
-[in English] Local brewery.
-Local brewery.
[♪ rock music plays]
Look, everyone's chuggin' it down.
-True.
-Sure looks good.
I'm jealous.
Nothing quite beats day drinking.
Yeah, while the sun's still out.
[in English] Oh, yeah!
Oh, yeah!
[narrator, in Japanese] The three of them
first head to a beer brewery.
[in English] Yeah!
-[in Japanese] It's huge!
-Huge.
What the heck?
[♪ music continues]
[Machu, in English] Ah, local brewery?
[in Japanese] Isn't it massive?
[♪ music stops]
-The entire place smells like beer.
-Look at these humongous vats.
[machinery whirring]
[in English] I'm Genta.
Nice to meet you. I'm Machu.
Hi, nice to meet you.
-I'm Shime.
-Great.
Nice to meet all of you.
You guys want to learn about brewing?
-Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Right.
Let's head up top.
[Genta] Wow.
This way? Oh.
-[in Japanese] Wow. I'm not even kidding.
-Right?
[brewery guide, in English] So, today
we are brewing a batch of
our flagship IPA, Modus Hoperandi.
This is our mash tun here.
[Genta] Ooh.
[brewery guide]
So, what's in there is this grain here.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
[brewery guide] And we turn the starch
inside the grain into sugar…
-Sugar.
-…that will be later turned into alcohol.
[Shime] Uh-huh.
-[brewery guide] You want to eat some?
-[Shime] Yeah.
-For real? Are you sure?
-Wow.
-[Machu] Really?
-Yeah.
[in Japanese] Are they edible?
It's good.
-Yum.
-It's a little bitter.
Right.
Don't they remind you of peanuts?
-Yep.
-It's tasty.
-[in English] Like peanuts?
-Like peanuts.
Mm-hmm. So, after this,
we rinse all that through
and it goes into
this kettle behind you here.
[in Japanese] Oh, wow. Ooh.
-Wow.
-Is it for fermentation?
[brewery guide, in English]
This is where we boil.
And we add the hops.
Uh-huh.
-Don't eat these ones.
-[Machu laughs]
You can smell them.
[exclaims]
[in Japanese] Wow.
-It already smells like beer.
-Sweet smell of beer.
It's definitely beer.
[brewery guide, in English]
So, from here to the finished product,
it can take anywhere
from two to six weeks.
But we've got a batch fresh
in the bright tank right now.
-You guys want to go try it out?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
All right.
Yeah.
-Let's go.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
[Genta, in Japanese] Crazy!
[Shime, in English] Wow.
So, these are our bright tanks.
After fermentation,
it comes here before it gets packaged.
Taste some right now.
-Really? Right now?
-Yeah. Right now.
Let's do it.
[Genta] I wanna drink.
[in Japanese]
It doesn't get any fresher than this.
It's freshly brewed.
Hot and fresh.
Can we really drink some here?
-[in English] Yeah. Of course.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
-All right. Do we have glasses?
-We'll catch back up.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
Cool.
-[in Japanese] That's insane.
-[Genta] Ooh.
[chuckles] This is crazy.
How pretty.
It's very pure.
[Machu] The vats are ginormous,
but the beer comes out in a trickle.
-Yeah.
-It's true. [laughs]
I love the way it comes out all at once.
Oh, man, it looks delicious!
Look at the foam. It's unreal.
I wanna use that foam to wash my face.
[Shime, Machu laugh]
So bubbly.
Fluffy foam.
Amazing.
-[in English] Wow. Fresh.
-Amazing.
-Here you are.
-Thank you so much.
-[in Japanese] Amazing.
-[in English] Let's go.
[in Japanese] Oh, no, the foam!
-Bottoms up!
-Enjoy!
Tasty! [laughs]
-It's seriously good.
-Is it?
How do I put it…
[Shime] You downed it.
[exclaims]
[in English] I love it.
-Now, that's good.
-Perfect.
-I'll have a sip then.
-Yep, yep, yep.
Bottoms up.
Yum. It goes down easily.
Goes down easy, huh?
I'm gonna take that as it was good?
-It tastes good.
-Yeah.
[in Japanese] That's delicious.
The bitterness is on spot,
and it's freshly brewed.
-It's even slightly fruity.
-It's fruity.
It's true.
-Yum!
-It goes down easy.
[in English] It tastes good.
-Yeah.
-Yeah, great.
Yeah.
[brewery guide laughs]
[Shime] You're chugging it.
I can go for the entire barrel.
-That's heavenly.
-Incredible.
-It's out of this world.
-Delicious. It's amazing. So good.
-[in English] Tastes good.
-So good?
-That's what we strive for.
-Yeah.
All right, guys. Thanks.
-Nice to meet y'all.
-Thank you so much.
-Yeah. Of course. Thanks.
-Thank you.
[brewery guide]
I hope you have fun in Colorado.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
[narrator, in Japanese]
Next, the trio heads to the bar
that serves the brewery's beer.
[Genta]
Don't you want to try a variety of drinks?
-Let's sample them all.
-I do.
-There's no shortage of options here.
-Don't you think the lineup is impressive?
Yeah.
-…and do a taste test.
-Yeah, yeah.
-[Machu] Oh, great idea.
-I'm up for it.
-[in English] Hey, everyone.
-Hey.
-Hi.
-Um, does everybody here drink beer?
-Uh, yeah.
-So, actually…
-Okay.
-What do you recommend?
Oh, man. Okay.
-Oh, man.
So, my favorite is the Rue B. Soho,
it's a grapefruit lager.
Uh-huh.
Um, but we also have a lot of really great
IPA options as well.
Is that the kind that you guys like?
-Yes.
-Okay, awesome.
So we have, um,
a really fruity couple of options.
We have a Tropical Hazy, The Hazy IPA,
and then we have a new one,
-it's called the Guava Stomper.
-Guava?
-Nice.
-It's really good.
-Oh, really?
-Do you guys wanna try some of those?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Also, I wanna try a dark lager.
-Ooh, yeah. We have a dark lager.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, and I think, um, we have
-the Modus Hoperandi as well.
-The Modus.
I think you guys might've done
a tour back there and tried it then.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Okay, cool.
Well, let me put a flight together and I
will have these right out for you to try.
-Okay. Appreciate it. Thank you.
-Awesome.
Oh. I'll put these in a glass for you.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
-[in Japanese] This place is amazing.
-I'm excited.
Me too.
Gotta try 'em all.
[Genta] Say, if there's a flavor
we particularly like…
-what if we grab a few bottles…
-[Shime] Good idea.
[Genta] …for the other guys?
-Then we can toast in Sedona.
-[Genta] I like that.
We'll sample the entire lineup,
then choose a couple…
-[server, in English] All right.
-Wow!
-[server] These are the Skaguas.
-[Machu laughs] Okay.
-[server] Skagua.
-[Genta] Beautiful.
All right, so what we have here
is the watermelon sugar-free.
We have the lemon,
and then this one is the grapefruit.
-[Genta] All right.
-[Shime] Yay.
-[Machu] So nice.
-[server] Yes. Enjoy.
-Thank you so much.
Yeah.
-[Shime, in Japanese] Awesome.
-Sick.
-[Machu] This is dope.
-What a cute setup.
I want to snap a photo of it.
[Machu] Let's take one then.
-I love this.
-Right?
I'll take it for you.
Right, thanks.
Get down to the glass's level.
Gotta include the beer.
Say cheese.
[camera shutter clicks]
Great photo.
-[Genta] Great. It's perfect.
-Which one?
-Cheers.
It's gonna be delicious.
Well? Are we ready
to declare our favorites?
-My fave…
-Here, go for it.
This one for me.
-Which is which?
-The dark one.
-This one's the IPA.
-What's this one called again?
We tried this one earlier.
I like the watermelon.
-Same.
-Oh.
This one's fruity
and only slightly bitter.
Is that right?
This one's fruity too.
There's a bitter aftertaste though.
[Shime] Wow.
Kinda like that, yeah.
[in English] I see. I see.
-[Genta, in Japanese] Do you want this?
-Yeah.
[Genta] I'll try a sip of this one then.
You're right.
-And this one…
-This one's fruity. I think so too.
-This one is more bitter.
-Yeah.
And this one's fruity too.
[Machu] Here.
-[Shime] It's delicious.
-Didn't expect that, huh?
I keep coming back to the IPA.
This one's my pick.
[Machu] Right?
-[Genta] Try this one. It's like…
-[Machu] What is it?
[Genta] It's got a different
flavor profile than these.
[Machu] Hold on.
I might have figured it out, yeah.
-[Shime] Have you decided?
-What?
[Machu] It's guava.
That's what they said earlier.
Let's ask.
Not lime?
But didn't they say it's guava?
Then that one might be the lime.
-No, I think it's guava.
-[Genta] Here it comes.
[Machu] I can't tell, I can't tell.
Know what,
we're about to find out whether I'm…
a genius.
-I just may be a genius.
-My bet's on lime.
Is it guava, or is it lime?
[Machu] Let's see who's right.
-All right.
-Nice.
-[server] How is it going?
-Can I just…
-Yeah, pretty good.
-Pretty good. Pretty good.
[server] All right.
So… Yeah.
This one is like a… a guava one?
[server] Yeah.
[Genta] Not a lime?
[server] Oh, that one right there?
Oh, you know, that one to me…
I think that one's the lime.
-[laughs] Yeah.
-[server] Well, have you smelled it?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-[server] Okay.
-It's maybe…
-[Machu laughs]
-Lime.
-[server] Do you smell any lime?
-Yeah? Then that's the one.
-[Machu] Really?
-[server] Yeah.
-He said guava.
[server] You can tell when you smell it.
-Yeah.
-[Machu] Okay…
[in Japanese] Wait, seriously?
[Shime, in English] Winner.
[server laughs]
Gen-chan winner.
[in Japanese] You know who
I think will like this? Chaka-chan.
True, I can see Chaka liking it.
Yeah. Also, Noel.
Might be Noel's thing.
-Shime and Shizu aren't keen on alcohol.
-You're right.
I'd pick non-alcoholic ones.
Good point,
Shizu and I don't drink much alcohol.
We'll take one of these three then.
[Shime] This isn't bad either.
Yum.
Shizuya might like it.
You're right. It's a good pick for Shizu.
-All right, pick one for Shizu.
-Shizu's?
He's big on fizzy drinks.
-He loves carbonated drinks.
-So…
-The grapefruit one's the fizziest drink.
-Ah. Oh, oh.
I can see that, yeah.
Let's go with
the grapefruit for Shizu then.
-[Genta] Mmm. Great pick.
-Nice.
-It's very Shizuya.
-[Genta, Shime laugh]
-Would Shizuya like it?
-One for Shizuya!
-Zuya-nii.
-[Genta] Zuya-nii!
Which one would Umi like?
There's a bitter taste
on top of the fruitiness.
It's bitter.
-I've decided.
-[Machu] So have I.
-Ready, go.
Ooh!
[Shime] That's decisive.
Then, Umi.
[Machu] For Noel…
Now imagine you're Noel.
[chuckles] What?
Nope, it's not him. I don't see it.
Since we came all this way,
let's pick a flavor he'd never expect.
[Genta] Exactly, you read my mind.
[in English] So, do you have…
So, not a sweetie.
-No sweet.
-[server] Okay. All right, yeah.
So you want something
that's not super sweet.
Do you want it to still be like an IPA?
-Yes.
-[Machu] Yeah.
[server] Okay.
Let me see what I can find for you.
-Thank you so much.
Thank you.
-[in Japanese] How kind.
-Right?
[Machu] So kind.
-[server] All right.
-[Genta] Oh, yeah.
-[Machu] All right. All right.
-[Genta] Wow.
[server] So, here I…
-Since you're in the Southwest…
-[Machu] Uh-huh.
[server] …you've got to try
the Southwest Coast IPA.
-[Machu] Okay.
-[Genta] Yeah, yeah.
[server] This one is a little less sweet
and we brewed it specifically to pair with
all of the fun stuff you can
get up to in the Southwest.
-Nice.
-Okay.
-[server] Yeah. Enjoy.
-I can try.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
-[server] Yeah.
-Thank you.
Oh.
[in Japanese] It's good.
[Genta] Wait, I'm kinda liking this one.
It goes down easy.
Light and easy, right?
I'm sold on this one.
-I think Noel will like it too.
-[Genta] Yeah.
-Let's do that then.
-[Machu] Nice, nice, nice.
We've made our picks.
[Shime] Think they'll like it?
We bought a ton of souvenirs.
-I won't deny that.
-True.
We got these drinks and the necklace.
-True. That's so true.
-Right?
I'm super excited.
-[in English] All right, I might…
-Here comes!
-I might be missing one.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
-Okay.
So I have the Southwest Coast IPA.
-Yeah.
Mexi Style Cold IPA.
-Okay.
-The Checkered Future IPA.
-Yeah.
-Hazy IPA, that's the one.
-Hazy IPA.
And then I have this
delicious lemon Skagua.
[in Japanese]
We're grabbing two just for Shizuya.
[Genta] These two for Shizuya.
-This one.
-All right.
-That's the whole set.
-Heck, yeah.
-[in English] We are Travis Japan!
-Travis Japan!
-[in Japanese] There we go!
-Don't you think they'll love it?
-They'll definitely be so happy.
I love the design.
-It's cute.
-Right?
You guys are gonna explore the town, yeah?
I thought it'd be fun to go shop around.
I'm ready to go chill.
I'm kinda in the mood to chill now.
-Are you going back to the hotel?
-Got it, okay.
-Yeah.
-[Shime] All right, see ya later.
Which way are we going?
-[Shime] If it works out then.
-Bye now.
-[Machu] He'll definitely flake on us.
-[Shime] Okay, well, enjoy your rest.
[Genta] Yeah.
-See ya.
-[Genta] See you later.
All right, it's time for me to enjoy
some alone time at the hotel.
This hotel is incredible.
You see this?
This place is amazing, huh?
I can access my room
without taking the elevator.
Just climb up
a flight of stairs.
Here I am.
Room 220.
Seriously,
those two never run out of energy.
The key…
Time to whip out my key.
Welcome to Matsuda's suite!
Isn't it amazing?
Apparently, this room…
is even featured on a book
about this hotel.
This room's special…
Apparently,
it's special for one reason or another.
Finally, we're here.
Here we are.
[light switch clicks]
[water running]
I'm growing a 'stache.
I'm not shaving once this trip.
Even just being out in the sun
saps my energy.
Right, right?
You can't beat this relaxation.
I'm gonna relax.
It's time for me to rest, guys.
I'm tapping out, yeah.
That picture right there…
that picture's always, like,
looking at me when I'm on the bed.
It sits dead center in my view.
It's a little creepy, don't you think?
And look at this one too.
You can see the reflection
of the bed on that mirror.
It's creepier than you'd expect.
All right.
Seriously, guys,
it's time for me to get some rest.
Bye-bye!
[narrator]
After recharging with a power nap,
Genta joined Shime and Machu,
who have returned from exploring the town,
at the saloon located on
the hotel basement floor.
[Shime] Awesome.
[narrator] The bar exudes a quiet luxury,
steeped in the Old Frontier charm.
[♪ blues music plays]
[in English] Hello.
-Hello.
-Hello. How are ya?
-Great.
-We are pretty good.
-Thank you.
-I'm just gonna give menus for y'all.
-Thanks so much.
-Thank you so much.
Yeah, of course.
Do you have local beer?
We do. Yeah, we have
a Mexican lager and a hazy IPA.
Ah, okay. Uh…
You wanna try one of those?
-Yes.
-Yeah, I recommend the Mexican lager.
-Yes. Yes, please.
-Perfect.
Two Mexican beer and…
-Orange juice.
-[server] Orange juice?
-OJ.
-[server] OJ? Yeah? Absolutely.
-Yeah.
[in Japanese]
Isn't this what Noel was talking about?
Ah. "Know when to stop," you mean?
-I mean, maybe.
-Like, don't black out?
Right, don't drink too much.
-Is that what he meant?
-Yep.
-Oh. Good point.
-That's a great guess.
Yeah. After all, look. The list's endless.
[Machu] True.
[Shime]
They've got all the alcohol in the world.
What was it… They call it
the living museum, I think?
-Right.
Durango is also
known as "The Living Museum."
This hotel's history goes way back too.
Just like the history
of the craft beer here.
-True.
-Good point, good point.
That's right.
There must be an explanation
behind her period costume too.
-Which one?
-Yeah, what's that about?
We've seen all sorts of period costumes.
[in English]
There's the orange juice for ya.
-Thank you so much.
-Oh, yeah.
[server] Of course, you guys.
-[Genta] Thank you so much.
-[server] I put the french fries in.
-[in Japanese] Shall we toast?
-Let's start with a toast.
Ready, go.
-Cheers.
-Yes. Cheers.
Oh!
Yum.
Wanna have a sip?
Yeah, I'll take a sip.
Lunchtime beer.
-Beer for lunch. Great way to dine.
-This is supreme.
-Indeed, yes.
-[Genta] It's delicious.
[Genta] Don't force yourself to drink.
-Just a sip, yeah?
-[Machu] It goes down easy.
It's not bitter, but rather fruity.
-Yeah.
-Isn't this one a Mexican beer?
Yep, it's Mexican.
Local beer, huh?
Seriously, Gen-chan,
while you were waiting…
[Noel] What'd I tell them?
"Know when to stop!"
I understand, though.
Durango's craft beers are top-notch.
Translated by Megumi Hunter